Souad El Mansouri

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

souadelmansouri2018@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

A Full-stack Developer with a high sense of responsibility, experience in open-source contributions, and remote teamwork. Developed a new feature for an educational, social network, enabling educators worldwide to create and share well-documented activities benefiting 1000s of students globally. Created and collaborated in 15+ React and RoR projects.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React.js, React native, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Material-UI, Formik, pdfmake, TypeScript, Solidity

Back-End: Python, Django, Rest APIs, Django-rest-framework, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Ai, NIp **Tools & Methods**: Git, GitHub, Docker, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD

Languages: English, French, Arabic

EXPERIENCE

UNSTRUCTURED STUDIO

Remote

Full-stack web developer

May 2022 - Mar 2023

- Enhanced the Zubhub open-source educational social network by finalizing and integrating 5+ additional functionalities to the new learning activities feature. (React/Django)
- Contributed to increasing user engagement by 10%.

<u>OUTREACHY</u> Remote

Outreachy'22 intern @unstructured studio Full-stack software developer

Jun 2022 – Aug 2022

• Led a 3-month internship project at <u>Unstructured Studio</u>, pioneering the development of Zubhub's learning activities feature using React/Django, resulting in the implementation of 4+ functionalities.

<u>MICROVERSE</u> Remote

Code Reviewer

Feb 2023 -Mar 2024

- Reviewed student's codebases to ensure code quality and performance
- Performed 300+ code reviews and gave developers advice on code clarity, style, and best practices.

GENIE.AI Remote

Software Engineer

Mar 2024-

 Developing middleware solutions to automate business operations by bridging the gap between AI technology and social media platforms.(Python/FastApi/Azure/Pydantic)

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full-stack Web Developer

Mar 2022 - Present

- Ebike Reservations: Web application that allows users to share, publish or hide their own e-bikes for renting and reserve published available ebikes for a period of time. (React/Ruby On Rails) Github repo link
- Document Analyzer: web app that leverages Hugging Face and OpenAl APIs to empower users to upload documents, seamlessly perform question-answering, and receive insightful summaries, enhancing document comprehension and analysis in a user-friendly interface.. (React/Django/Docker/NIp) <u>Github repo link</u>

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

• Mentored 4 junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews. and provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program which helped 100% of them finish the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

 Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, JavaScript, React, and Redux.

FACULTY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF MARRAKECH

Sep 2015 - Oct 2016

Bachelor's Degree in Distributed Computer Systems

- Graduated with honors
- Learned the development and adaptation of flexible, secure, and reliable distributed applications.